THIS STORY IS A FICION, AND ALL NAMES OF FIGURES ND ORGANIZATIONS ARE FICTITIOUS.
（本作所有人物、组织名均为虚构）
MOREOVER, THE STORY HAS NO RELATION TO REAL-LIFE INCIDENTS AND EVENTS.
（与任何特定事件或现象无关）
I accept my loss.
我认输
-You've improved, Basen. -No.
-你进步了 马闪 -过奖了
I merely push through with force.
我只是靠着蛮力使剑罢了
I'm still no match for you, Sir Jinshi.
我仍然不是壬氏大人的对手
But that is a great force you have.
但你的力量真的很大
As expected from the Ma clan.
不亏是马氏家族的成员
So how is she, Gaoshun?
高顺 她好吗？
The apothecary, I mean.
我说的是那个药师
How do you mean?
这是什么意思？
Has she gained a little weight?
她胖了一些吗？
She's slowly gaining it back.
她的体重渐渐恢复了
I see. However…
了解 但是…
Do you even know why this was forbidden?
你知道为什么要禁用白粉吗？
I'm saying it's poison, damn it!
我不是说了吗？那有毒
I never imagined she had such a side to her.
我没料到她有这样的一面
Are you all right?
您还好吗？
-What? Why? -You worry about her quite a lot.
-为什么这么问？ -您相当担心她
No, it's nothing.
不 没什么
I knew it was here!
我就知道这儿有
All right!
好耶！
Another one!
这儿也有
Here too?
这儿也有耶
Where should I eat this? In the kitchen?
我该在哪儿吃呢？膳房吗？
But it'd be troublesome if they ask where I got this…
但如果他们问起 我怎么会有这些食材会很麻烦…
Oh, before that…
对哦 在那之前…
Wow, it looks so good!
看起来好好吃
Thanks for doing this again, Maomao!
猫猫 谢谢你又带这些过来
The other attendants are so kind to share dim sum
猫猫的前辈侍女也很好心 每当我们开茶会的时候
each time we have tea together!
都会分享点心给我们
Eat more!
多吃一点
You need to get more fat.
你得多长一些肉
Don't be shy!
别客气啦
-Oh, did you hear? -Huh?
-对了 你有听说那件事吗？ -什么？
An Imperial Court palace woman
宫中一名宫女
succeeded in seducing a eunuch who's famous for hating women!
成功引诱了讨厌女人出名的武官哦
I see.
是哦
-How do you think she did it? -I have no idea.
-你觉得她是怎么办到的？ -我不知道
She used a stimulant potion!
听说她用了春药
Stimulant potion?
春药？
It's that one.
是那个啊
What's wrong, Maomao?
怎么了吗 猫猫？
Oh, it's nothing.
没什么啦
It's probably unrelated. I think…
应该跟这件事无关 应该吧…
Good morning.
早上好
Hey, miss! What do you need today?
小姑娘 你今天需要些什么？
I have something to ask you in confidence.
我想请你私下帮个忙
What is it?
什么事？
-It's this. -Wow!
-是这个 -哇！
It's the first matsutake mushroom of the year!
这是今年第一批松茸！
I'm glad you seem to like these.
很高兴你喜欢
We need coal!
我们需要木炭
I'll also bring some soy paste and salt!
我也会拿一些酱油和盐
All in all,
总而言之
I've built a good relationship with the quack doctor.
我和这位庸医建立了良好关系
This is the stuff!
就是这一味
It looks ready now.
看起来可以吃了
Drizzle some soy paste, add a little salt…
滴一些酱油 加一点盐
Here you are.
请用
It's so good!
好好吃
Now, we're partners in crime.
这样我们就是共犯了
Doctor!
太医
Could you…?
可否请你…
Make something to cure my curse?
做一些解咒的药物呢？
A curse?
解咒？
-What is this about? -It's this.
-发生了什么事？ -请看
That's a pretty bad rash.
皮疹的状况相当严重
Maybe some ointment first?
总之先做一些药膏？
Will you make me some?
你可以做一些吗？
Sure.
包在我身上
So, what is this curse?
你说的诅咒是怎么回事？
This happened in the evening two nights ago.
这是前晚发生的事
The trash produced
后宫的垃圾
in the rear palace is burned in the fire on the west.
会运到西侧烧掉
I was working that night like always, then…
我跟往常一样在晚上工作 然后…
What is it?
这是什么？
A woman's clothing? The sleeves are burnt.
女人的衣服？袖子被烧焦了
And is this a wood tablet?
这是木简吗？
It bothered me a little,
虽然我有点在意
but I threw them in the fire as is. But then…
但我还是把木简丢进火里 然后…
It's a curse! That's why my hands are like this…
这是个诅咒 所以我的手才会变成这样…
Was the flame you saw this color?
你见到的火焰是这种颜色吗？
If not this, then this.
不是这个的话 是这个吗？
I can make this one too.
这个我也做得出来
Miss, what is this?
小姑娘 这是什么？
It works the same way as fireworks.
它的运作方式就跟烟花一样
Some things can change the color of the flame when it burns.
有些东西在燃烧的时候 会改变火焰的颜色
So what about this hand?
那这只手呢？
My guess is something was attached to the wood tablet.
我猜是某种东西沾到木简上了
The rash came from coming into contact with that.
因为接触到那个东西而起疹子了
Apply this ointment and see if it works.
擦擦这个药膏 看看是否有用
Thank you very much.
感激不尽
Her medicine always works well!
她的药一向效果很好
You'll get better in no time!
你很快就会痊愈
Wonderful. As expected of the apothecary.
太精采了 不亏是药师
Sir Jinshi!
壬氏大人
I'll prepare some tea right away.
我立刻去准备茶水
How do you do, Sir Jinshi?
壬氏大人 你近来可好？
Did you need something?
有什么需要吗？
Are you saying I can't talk to you if I don't need something?
如果没事 我就不能跟你说话吗？
No, not at all.
没有 没有那回事
Come with me.
跟我来一下
Here you are, Sir Jinshi…
壬氏大人 茶水来了…
How many colors are there?
有几种颜色？
I don't know the exact number.
我不太确定有几种
How do you apply the color, then?
那是要如何上色？
With salt, you can apply color by dissolving it in water.
用盐巴 把盐巴溶在水里 就能够改变颜色
I know there are certain dyes
我知道有某些染料
that dissolve with things like oil, not water.
会溶解在油里 而不是水里
But this isn't my area of expertise, so I don't know.
但我不是这方面的专家 所以我也不确定
I see.
原来如此
If we're finished here, I'll be off.
如果没我的事的话 小的先告退了
Wait.
等一下
What is it?
有何吩咐？
I love mushrooms too.
我也很喜欢土瓶蒸
I'm expecting good work, Apothecary.
就拜托你咯 药师
So he knew…
被他发现了…
I'll go out tomorrow… To look for them…
我明天会出门寻找的…
Search for those who've suffered a burn to their arm recently.
找出那些最近手臂烧伤的人
Understood, sir.
遵命
A colored wood tablet is probably a code…
上色的木简可能是一种暗号…
Do they go through the trouble of making a code
因为某个不能公开的消息
because the information can't be made public?
他们大费周章做了暗号？
But what could that be…?
但会是什么呢？
It's not my business, really.
那不关我的事
It's nothing a poison tester should meddle in.
这不是试毒人该介入的事
Thank you.
谢谢
That one goes there.
那个放到那儿
I'm back.
我回来了
Welcome home…
你回来啦
Maomao! Perfect timing.
猫猫 来得正是时候
Can you put this on?
把这个穿上好吗？
I have a bad feeling…
我有不好的预感…
What is this?
这是怎么回事？
The costume for the garden party, obviously!
当然是参加游园会时的服装啊
The garden party?
游园会？
Twice a year, the Emperor and the higher-ups gather
一年举办两次 皇上和高官
at the court garden to enjoy
会聚在皇宫的庭园享乐
performances and a meal.
看表演和享用美食
The Emperor isn't married yet,
皇上尚未立后
so he has no consort.
所以他没有皇后 对吧？
In that case,
这样的话
He is to take the highest status concubines.
他就得带最高阶级的妃子赴宴
Highest status concubine…
最高阶级的妃子…
The most likely candidates for the next consort, the high-ranking concubines.
上级妃是最有可能 成为下一任皇后的人选
The highest ranking concubines…
正一品的嫔妃…
The four high-ranking concubines.
正一品的嫔妃有四位
The Precious Concubine, Concubine Gyokuyou.
贵妃玉叶妃
The Wise Concubine, Concubine Lihua.
贤妃梨花妃
The Virtuous Concubine, Concubine Lishu.
德妃里树妃
The Pure Concubine, Concubine Ah-Duo.
淑妃阿多妃
At the last party, Ladies Gyokuyou and Lihua
上一次玉叶娘娘和梨花娘娘
were absent because they were heavily pregnant.
因为到了怀孕后期而不克参与
So this time, all four ladies are to gather!
所以这一次四位娘娘都会一起出席
So what are we doing there?
那我们到时要做什么？
Nothing, really.
什么都不用做
We're the guests invited to this party,
我们是受邀参加宴会的客人
so we just have to stay with the Emperor.
所以只需要待在皇上身边
Sometimes, the officials come to greet us.
有时候官员会前来致意
So don't forget to smile.
所以要记得微笑
Is everyone to attend?
所有人都得赴宴吗？
Of course!
当然咯
The first showing of Princess Lingli,
这次还是铃丽公主初次亮相
the four ladies gathering… This year is important!
四大娘娘聚在一起 还有满满活动
This is a war! We have to take this on!
这是战争 不留心注意可是不行的
Let's do this!
全力奋战！
Lady Gyokuyou already has very few attendants.
玉叶娘娘的侍女本来就很少了
A newcomer can't be absent…
新来的不可能缺席…
And if there are meals, the poison tester needs to be there.
而且如果有食物的话 试毒人就得到场
We should stuff your chest area.
看来该在你的胸衣里塞一些东西
I'll also add a bit to your hips. Is that okay?
我也会给你的臀部 垫一些东西 可以吗？
I'll let you decide.
由你决定吧
The makeup will be impeccable too!
妆容也得完美无瑕才行
We have to hide those freckles sometimes.
有时得盖住那些雀斑才行
Watching performances outdoors
在刮风的户外
where it's windy, eating meals,
看表演、吃饭
smiling at the officials who come our way…
面带微笑地对经过的官员打招呼
My bladder will need to be as strong as iron.
我的膀胱得跟铁打的一样才行
In that case…
这样的话…
This should work.
这应该会有用
It smells so good!
味道好香啊
What are you making?
你在做什么？
-I'm making ginger and orange candy. -Candy?
-我正在做橙子姜糖 -糖？
Orange peels improve blood flow
橙子皮能够促进血液循环
and ginger can warm the body.
姜则能让身子暖起来
Is this for the garden party?
是为了游园会而准备的吗？
Yes. I also made this.
对 我也做了这个
I sewed a pocket to my undershirt.
我在内衣里缝了一个口袋
If I place warming stones inside, I won't get as cold.
如果在里面放温热的石头 就不会觉得那么冷了
-Maomao! -Huh?
-猫猫 -干嘛？
Please, will you make that for everyone?
拜托你 给每个人都做一份
Yes, ma'am…
好的…
Once you get used to customs,
一旦养成习惯…
I guess you don't think about these small things.
就不会动脑筋想这些小事呢
A little creativity can go a long way.
一点创意能发挥很大的作用
-Come in. -Please make one for me too.
-请进 -也给我做一个
-Me too… -Yes, sir.
-我也是… -遵命
Can you show me how to make that?
你可以教我怎么做吗？
Please!
拜托你
The seamstress in charge of the Emperor's clothes and His chef…
皇帝的御用绣女和御厨都来了…
Wow, so cold!
好冷啊
I'm finally finished!
终于做完了
Tomorrow's the big day.
就是明天了
I'll make that just in case.
以防万一 把那个东西做好吧
About the search for those with burns on their arm…
关于找出手臂烧伤的人这事…
You haven't found them yet?
你还没找到吗？
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
The garden party…
游园会…
I hope nothing happens there…
希望不会出什么事…
You're so beautiful, Lady Gyokuyou!
玉叶娘娘 你好美哦
Red suits you so well!
红色好适合您
How beautiful she is…
真的好美哦
So it's true that she looks the best in red in this whole country.
难怪会被称为 “举国最适合红色的美女”
You're more beautiful than anyone.
是啊 您比任何人都美
Thank you, everyone. And these are for you.
谢谢你们 这些是要给大家的
I need to leave my mark
我得留下我的记号
so that no one unsavory targets you.
这样才不会有闲杂人等 对你们图谋不轨
Maomao.
猫猫
Listen, Maomao.
你听好 猫猫
You're my attendant, okay?
你是我的侍女哦
Thank you so much, my lady.
小的感激不尽
Got you!
抓到你了
Um, well…
等一下…
Let's do your makeup!
我们替你化妆咯
Go be your cutest self.
展现出你最可爱的一面吧
I'll wipe your face and apply perfume oil.
我要把你的脸洗干净 再擦香油
And those freckles of yours…
然后把你的雀斑…
Here we go!
来咯
-Huh? -Maomao?
-什么？ -猫猫？
-No way! -Why?
-不是吧？ -为什么？
Maomao, you…
猫猫 你…
Dang. They know now.
可恶 被她们知道了
All right. Let's go.
好 出发吧
All right, then, Concubine Lishu. See you later.
那么 里树妃 我们晚点见
Yes!
好
Sir Jinshi…
壬氏大人…
Last up is the Precious Concubine, Concubine Gyokuyou.
最后一位是贵妃玉叶妃
Is his commitment to Concubine Gyokuyou strong
他对玉叶妃照顾有加
because he found a toy he likes?
是因为发现了喜欢的玩具吗？
What can I do with him?
真是令人头疼的大人哪
Maomao, you helped us out a lot.
猫猫 你真是帮了我们大忙
I'm happy to be of use.
我很乐意效劳
How do you do, Concubine Gyokuyou?
玉叶妃 你近来可好？
How do you do?
近来可好？
You look beautiful in red as always, Concubine Gyokuyou.
玉叶妃穿上红色总是这么美
While decorative, you look somewhat mystical.
尽管雍容华贵 却带有一丝神秘感
It's probably due to your beautiful green eyes, Concubine Gyokuyou.
可能是因为您那美丽的绿色眼眸
Thank you.
谢谢
All right, so how is the princess doing?
好的 这位公主还好吗？
How do you do, Sir Jinshi?
壬氏大人 你近来可好？
Oh, oh… It's you, Apothecary.
噢…是你啊 药师
You're wearing foundation?
你上妆了？
No, I'm not.
我没有
But your freckles are gone.
但你的雀斑都不见了
Because I got rid of them.
对 因为我除掉了
With makeup, right?
靠化妆 对吧？
They went away because I removed my makeup.
因为在我卸妆之后 雀斑就消失了
You're not making any sense.
你这话实在让人丈二金刚摸不着头脑
You're contradicting yourself.
根本自相矛盾
Oh, this is a pain.
好烦人
I should've just said yes.
早知道说“对”就好了
I was applying makeup daily,
我每天都会化妆
using dried clay to draw the freckles on.
用干掉的黏土化上雀斑
What you've been seeing every day is my face with makeup.
壬氏大人每天看到的 其实是我上了妆之后的容貌
Makeup isn't simply for making someone beautiful.
化妆并不是只会让人变漂亮而已
Why do such a thing?
你为什么要这么做？
You really want to know?
你真的想知道吗？
It's so that I'm not dragged away to a back alley.
这样我才不会被抓进暗巷
Even in the pleasure district, there are men starving for women.
就算是在花街 还是有对女人很饥渴的男人
Broke men, violent men, and men with venereal diseases.
没有钱又残暴的男人 染上性病的男人也很多
A small, scraggy and ugly woman would rarely be a target.
一个又瘦又小又丑的女人 鲜少会成为目标
Has that happened to you?
你遇过这种事？
It was just an attempt.
未遂罢了
I was carried off by kidnappers instead.
但我倒是被人口贩子掳走了
My makeup was falling off.
我的妆掉了
They thought that maybe I could be sold.
他们觉得勉强能把我卖掉吧
I see…
原来如此…
I apologize for my poor management.
抱歉 是我管理不周
It doesn't matter.
没关系啦
Whether it's illegal kidnapping, or legally selling off children,
不管是非法绑架 还是非法把孩子卖掉
it's all the same to those who buy.
对买家来说都一样
This doesn't infuriate you?
这样不会让你生气吗？
Of course it does.
当然会
But it's not your fault, Sir Jinshi.
但这不是壬氏大人的错
I'm sorry…
很抱歉…
He's being meek. That's rare.
这么率直 还真难得
That hurts.
弄痛我了
I see. It's for you.
是哦 这是给你的
I'll see you at the party.
我们宴会见
Huh?
什么？
A man's hair clip?
男人的发簪？
But why…?
这是为什么？
-So cool! -I'm so jealous!
-好棒哦 -我好嫉妒你
I want one too!
我也想要一个
I don't mind giving it, but how can I share it?
我不介意送人 但我该怎么分？
You already broke my promise?
你这么快就失信于我咯？
Huh?
什么意思？
You're not just my attendant anymore.
你再也不是我专属的侍女了呢
What does that mean…?
那是什么意思？
It's time.
时候到了
The garden party is about to start.
游园会就要开始了
PREVIEW OF NEXT EPISODE
（下集预告）
Next episode, "The Garden Party."
下一集 《游园会》
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：欧德慧